Krénusz Bence

Principal Data Scientist / Machine Learning Engineer

REMOTE

Download the pdf

bence.krenusz@gmail.com

+36707998786

Skills

Data Science

Over 5+ years of Machine Learning experience I have gained heuristic knowledge regarding the End-to-End Machine Learning process flow. Through my career I was fortunate enough to experience the trust of many Teams over several Company. Started from Junior and became a Lead over 3 and a half year. With the Junior position I have built up the stable base of my Data Science career, the enthusiasm in both statistical and computational mathematics help me to understand the problems not only from Data Science but also from Machine Learning Engineer perspective. The Senior position at a new Company reinforced me, that I have chosen the right path and, that my knowledge and skills are highly required and appreciated over a various field of Applied Machine Learning. Developing more and more sophisticated solutions and building up reliability and understanding with Stakeholders and the business, I have earned the principal position in Data Science. I have started to build up my own Data Science team and hence my responsibility started to increase rapidly. Practicing leading position help our global Team to achieve higher number of quality project solutions much faster.

Solution Architecture

The up-to-date solutions tend to exclusively use Cloud solution to achieve project automation and deployment. Working day-today-day closely with Solution Architecture for projects it is crucial to involve both the Data Science and Data Engineering perspectives.

Data Engineering and Business Intelligence

Working closely with the Data Engineer and Data Analyst colleagues in a small team I have gained visibility on the processes beyond Machine Learning (e.g., ETL and SSIS; Power BI and Tableau). From the Cloud to the On-Premises solutions, We have walked through the possibilities to find the best fit for our use cases from the Data Engineering and Data Science point of view. Regarding the Business Intelligence, it was part of my job to gain experience in different BI apps, where I got familiar with the logic of queries and custom visualizations. Due to my Python and R knowledge, the embedded script features in these platforms made this process easier.

Tools

- Python
- R AWS

Azure

- Microsoft Power BI
- S3/Blob • SQL
- PyCharm VS Code
- Jupyter Notebook
- Github Copilot

Libraries

- Numpy
- Pandas

SqlAlcemy

- Matplotlib
- Seaborn
- Plotly
- PyTorch(main)
- Tensorflow/Keras ScikitLearn

Experience

Jabil EMS - Principal Data Scientist / Machine Learning Engineer

From 1st of January 2022

Strategical and Technical Lead of the Data Science Team:

- Managing the Team throughout diverse project space and applying strategical decisions following Key Principals. Delegating tasks considering the strengths of the Team members.

- Working closely with Data Engineers and Solution Architects to cover the E2E solution as effective as possible. - Strictly following the guidelines of Continuous Education and Research to be up to date in all applied Data Science field.
- Applying State-of-the-Art Deep Learning solutions (e.g. Transformer architectures) to achieve the maximum effectiveness in Prescriptive Maintenance.
- Enhancing classic Statistical Predictive analytics with ML and DL and with embedded Parallelization to create a Scalable solution on Enterprise level. - Experimenting with Deep Reinforcement Learning and Virtual and Real Simulation environments to create Robotic solution for Warehouse optimization.

Jabil EMS - Senior Data Scientist / Machine Learning Engineer

From 1st of December 2020

Developing and implementing various e2e Machine Learning solutions satisfying Business needs, following Lean AI methodology Coding in Python, Developing from scratch or Customizing various OpenSource solutions

Nokia - Data Scientist / Machine Learning Engineer

From 1st of June 2018

Leading the technical solution (of Python programming) to solve Business problems such as Predicting Supply Chain Delivery variables and Sales Opportunity information to optimize Resources and Sales Outcome. Responsible for the End to End Automation solution for the Machine Learning Environment.

Developing predictive models in order to forecasting Human Resource needs for particular locations.

Support the project which Predicting Demand information as Data Science assistant (Time Series analysis). Support the project targeting product mapping with Market Basket analysis.

Supporting NLP project targeting customer satisfaction content.

Support the Analytics Community with Deep Machine Learning and Python programming knowledge.

Achieved 1st place on Datathon - International Predictive Analytics Competition

Udemy, Kaggle - Data Science Preparation

Feb 2018 - Jun 2018

I have completed the Python programming for Data Science course on Udemy, which was in perfect connection with my previous Python (Numpy, Pandas, Seaborn, Matplotlib, Scikit Learn) which was required to became a Data Scientist. In addition I have looked into the R programming language, and started to gain knowledge. When I have received my certificate I have turned my direction to the Kaggle competition platform, where I have faced myself with Online Competition for Data Scientists: It was a Regression problem. My job was to predict the sales price for each house in the test dataset. For each Id in the test set, I must had to predict the value of the SalePrice variable. Right after I have started to seek for Data Scientist positions to find my required Business challenges.

IT Services Hungary Kft. - System Admin/Data Analyst

Jun 2016 - Feb 2018

In addition to my daily responsibilities i have started to learn Python programming by myself. I have explored the main logic of the language and the different programming styles. I have completed an exercise series which gave me the required knowledge to take an advanced course.

Evosec Kft. - Camera/Fire alarm installer

Sep 2015 - Sep 2016

Education

Udemy Academy

Data Science Certification

Topics of the Course: Programming with Python NumPy with Python Using pandas Data Frames to solve complex tasks Use pandas to handle Excel Files Web scraping with python to SQL Use matplotlib and seaborn for data visualizations Use plotly for interactive visualizations Machine Learning with SciKit Learn, including: Linear Regression K Nearest Neighbors K Means Clustering Decision Trees Random Forests Natural Language Processing Neural Nets and Deep Learning Support Vector Machines

Óbuda University, Donát Bánki Faculty of Mechanical Engineering

Mechanical Engineering Degree (Bsc)

2013-2017

Eötvös Loránd University

Matematics and Physics Studies

2011-2013

Hobbies

Currently focusing on a wide areas of sports. After 8 years of Judo I have started to do more independent sports such as climbing, tennis, squash, skiing, swimming and street workout. In addition I really like to hike and bike.

Bence Krénusz | <u>bence.krenusz@gmail.com</u>